<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Altcoin Trading</title>
    <description>Altcoin Trading is the forex of cryptocurrencies, with bitcoin as the base currency.</description>
    <link>https://www.altcointrading.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.altcointrading.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 01:47:28 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 01:47:28 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>PSA: Don't send ETH from Bitstamp to Bitfinex</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Apparently, the newly launched ETH trading on Bitstamp comes with an unpleasant surprise: If you withdraw ETH, the withdrawal is processed via a smart contract, &lt;strong&gt;which is not indicated on the ETH withdrawal page&lt;/strong&gt; - there is only a fineprint note below the withdrawal page’s fold that says “Please make sure that the receiving party supports Ethereum transactions generated from smart contracts prior to initiating an ETH withdrawal”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you happen to withdraw from Bitstamp to Bitfinex, your deposit will be confirmed on the blockchain but your money will not be credited because Bitfinex doesn’t accept deposits from smart contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ll still receive the money though. The money you didn’t know was sent via a smart contract. Because the receiving wallets are not using a smart contract themselves, so that they could make the transaction bounce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a time to be alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/bitfinex/comments/6x792r/bitfinex_deposit_eth_from_smart_contract_wallet/&quot;&gt;Thread on r/bitfinex where you can leave your support ticket number&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The support is at Poloniex level at the moment: too many users having the same issue, no tickets resolved. The only thing that sparks some “hope” is a recent tweet from Bitfinex: Apparently, they &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bitfinex/status/900646338941128704&quot;&gt;solve deposit “errors” for a $25 processing fee&lt;/a&gt;. I say “errors” because they were talking about sending BCH to an old BTC wallet, which is not really an error since the blockchain got duplicated so the address exists on BCH too if it existed on BTC before the fork. It’s not as much a payment for an error as a … payment for something that is invented to solve a problem which doesn’t really exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway! Main thing is we have a new frontend interface boys!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:18:50 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.altcointrading.net/bitifinex-eats-your-eth</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.altcointrading.net/bitifinex-eats-your-eth</guid>
        
        
        <category>trading</category>
        
        <category>bitfinex</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Demand for cryptocurrency in Asia just got less mysterious</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;North Korea has fired a missile that flew over northern Japan before crashing into the sea, the Japanese government says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-41078187&quot;&gt;BBC News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;North Korea has launched a ballistic missile that overflew Japan, an aggressive step the country has not taken in almost 20 years and which will undermine protracted US efforts to bring the nuclear aspirant to the negotiating table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/46910d8c-d958-3e46-ac69-8c739cbf052b&quot;&gt;FT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://data.altcointrading.net/img/gold.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as the news was out, BTCUSD shot up, gold got what the cryptocurrency traders would call &lt;em&gt;a green dildo&lt;/em&gt;, and USDJPY got what cryptocurrency traders call &lt;em&gt;rekt&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://data.altcointrading.net/img/usdjpy.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/BitcoinMarkets/comments/6wh1vp/daily_discussion_monday_august_28_2017/dm97mhc/&quot;&gt;someone on Reddit noted&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;To me this makes Bitcoin’s sudden popularity in South Korea and Japan much less mysterious. I really didn’t understand it before.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s of course not only Bitcoin: There was a whole ETH frenzy at one point and more recently, South Korean exchange &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Monero/comments/6vwlfl/hello_im_korean/&quot;&gt;Bithumb listed XMR just the other day&lt;/a&gt; which coincided with its massive bull run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://data.altcointrading.net/img/xmr.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 01:01:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.altcointrading.net/korea-missile-cryptocurrency</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.altcointrading.net/korea-missile-cryptocurrency</guid>
        
        
        <category>trading</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trezor devices have serious security vulnerability</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just yesterday, Trezor released a security update. It updated your firmware to version 1.5.2 as older versions of firmware could make your seedphrase visible to someone who’d steal the device, took it apart and flashed it with a hacked-up firmware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.trezor.io/trezor-firmware-security-update-1-5-2-5ef1b6f13fed&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the official story from Satoshi Labs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is important to note that this is not a remote execution attack. To exploit this issue, an attacker would need physical access to a disassembled TREZOR device with uncovered electronics. It is impossible to do this without destroying the plastic case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In order to exploit this issue, an attacker would have to break into the device, destroying the case in the process. They would also need to flash the device with a specially-crafted firmware. If your device is intact, your seed is safe, and you should update your firmware to 1.5.2 as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;With firmware 1.5.2, this attack vector is eliminated and your device is safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it happens, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@Zero404Cool/trezor-security-glitches-reveal-your-private-keys-761eeab03ff8&quot;&gt;the unofficial version&lt;/a&gt; is a lot worse:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The frantic patch creation we see now, before any coins have been lost (apparently), is because the &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.defcon.org/DEF%20CON%2025/DEF%20CON%2025%20presentations/DEFCON-25-Datko-and-Quartier-Breaking-Bitcoin-Hardware-Wallets.pdf&quot;&gt;issue was talked about at DEF CON 25&lt;/a&gt;. All Trezors, regardless of the firmware, use a chip that is vulnerable. According to the author of the article linked above, the chip will always be vulnerable in some way and Trezors are not safe unless all devices are replaced with ones that use safer chips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*wZCWyhLJHmg_6S2XqFwdTQ.jpeg&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Trezor so far greatly downplays the importance of this hack. There is no long-term access needed to copy all your secret information from Trezor using this hack, &lt;strong&gt;it can be done just in 15 seconds&lt;/strong&gt;. If your Trezor is stolen, you don’t even have time to transfer you funds to a new address. &lt;strong&gt;Government authorities can access all your Bitcoins and other crypto currencies without even asking for your consent. If you are crossing an international border, TSA can easily check your balances, etc.&lt;/strong&gt; IRL, Trezor is as safe as leaving your cash or wallet on the table. On top of all that, your Trezor can be restored to its original state or replaced with identical Trezor with the same configuration, you wouldn’t even notice any difference until it is too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exploit surely now can be done in 15 seconds at the airport since the &lt;a href=&quot;https://satoshibox.com/fwipady7nvbqoqreeso4cf82&quot;&gt;source code for it is public&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The key to performing this hack is simply connecting two pins inside the Trezor device at the right time, even paperclip is suitable for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Only a simple version of this hack requires the disassembly of Trezor. A more advanced version also exists. No disassembly is required!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author linked a satoshibox file with an exploit for the new firmware (1.5.2) but the link is broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-can-you-do&quot;&gt;What can you do?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn on password protection&lt;/strong&gt;. Passwords in Trezor create a 25th word of a seedphrase. Trezor claims password protection makes the devices safe against this exploit, it is for researchers now to prove or disprove that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep your Trezor in a vault, don’t have it on you when you cross borders.&lt;/strong&gt; You could have done better with a paper wallet though, or simply with a seedphrase note, couldn’t you?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build your own cold storage solution.&lt;/strong&gt; Back in the day, people used to use a spare clean computer with Armory or Electrum. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/goatpig/BitcoinArmory/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;BitcoinArmory is maintained again&lt;/a&gt; but Electrum is the wallet that gets forked to support your altcoin of the month. When you have doubts as to whether to trust a wallet software, like many people had with Bitcoin Cash wallet Electron, you can always install it on a virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 14:18:25 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.altcointrading.net/trezor-hack</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.altcointrading.net/trezor-hack</guid>
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
        
        <category>altcoins</category>
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bitstamp launches Ethereum trading tomorrow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bitstamp sent a reminder to their customers today that Ethereum trading is starting soon - Thursday, 17 August 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It gives us great pleasure to announce that we will be launching ETH for trading with &lt;strong&gt;BTC, USD and EUR&lt;/strong&gt; tomorrow, Thursday, 17 August!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ether deposits and withdrawals will open at 9.00 a.m. (UTC) on that date, with full trading functionalities commencing at 1.00 pm (UTC) .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FREE TRADING will be available on these pairs until 1 October&lt;/strong&gt;, with other generous discounts to follow until the end of the year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bitstamp.net/s/email_images/trading-news@2x.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 18:37:48 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.altcointrading.net/bitstamp-ethereum</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.altcointrading.net/bitstamp-ethereum</guid>
        
        
        <category>trading</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bitfinex is not planning to resolve the banking issues for retail customers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Phill G. Potter of Bitfinex (PGP) did an interview on Whalepool’s teamspeak just now. PGP used to be a regular on there but over the past few weeks there was no sight of him - it is not so hard to imagine he’d be bombarded with questions for hours the minute he’d log in these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the interview he spoke about the Bcash distribution, the new altcoins that are getting listed on Bitfinex and the ongoing fiat withdrawal issues - the banking issues being the only point where he actually said something surprising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know, some months ago Bitfinex started having issues with their banking routes and had to stop fiat withdrawals. That also influenced people who weren’t using the fiat withdrawal and also those who didn’t even trade on Bitfinex because Bitfinex was removed from indexes for futures markets because an exchange without fiat withdrawals is bound to have bullish bias on cryptocurrencies that has nothing to do with the state of the market. Until now Bitfinex people kept making it clear that this fiat issue was being worked on and hopefully new routes would be set up. In the meantime, withdrawals were enabled for several bigger customers and for people with access to banking in Taiwan which is where Bitfinex banks. Traders took this for a good sign and were expecting the situation would be back in normal soon. Today though PGP explained that the banking issues won’t change from what is it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to PGP, it wouldn’t pay off to Bitfinex to enable withdrawals for average the retail trader. He said the banks “don’t like to see many small transactions each day, it is harder to do AML/KYC for the USD routes and other fiat currencies, too”. Apparently enabling crypto-fiat routes for the retail would lead to more disruptions in the future anyway so it is not worth it for Bitfinex to do it. The way it works these days is if you are a big enough whale you already have fiat routes enabled, unless you’re new in which case you should talk to customer service. PGP explained the banking will probably stay available for the (few) regulars as they are KYC’d and known, while others will have to put up with crypto withdrawals and realize the profit via Kraken or Bitstamp if they want to. Effectively Bitfinex is trying to outsource this hassle to the exchanges that don’t have their fiat routes blocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the other things that PGP was talking about was the Bcash distribution the rules of which were changed after the distribution happened: ,,There is a lot of amateur laywers on Reddit but we have received no legal claims or complaints,” he explained and added a justification - the policy was changed so that people who hedged in such a way they didn’t have exposure to BTC would get no BCH, in other words in favor of people who had a position in BTC. Bitfinex always reserves the right to change their terms at any moment so there is not much you can do if you tried to game the system and were caught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PGP’s explanation as to why Bitfinex suddenly lists tokens that are unheard of amounted to &lt;em&gt;there’s money in it&lt;/em&gt; although it was said in better words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will be updated with a link to the YouTube video of the teamspeak interview once it’s uploaded. To catch the next event connect to &lt;a href=&quot;https://whalepool.io/connect/teamspeak&quot;&gt;https://whalepool.io/connect/teamspeak&lt;/a&gt; - the rumor has it John Bollinger will be coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rhu4c8sL0AE&quot;&gt;Link to Youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.altcointrading.net/bitfinex-banking</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.altcointrading.net/bitfinex-banking</guid>
        
        
        <category>trading</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anonymous coins on the Apple App Store</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Anonymous coins have always been a concern for the App Store as allegedly they didn’t want to be linked to illicit activities. If you are a DASH holder though, your situation regarding wallets is a bit less bleak than what’s normal for crypto right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The new official DASH wallet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DASH wallet app was released just yesterday to the Apple App Store. It is a cryptocurrency wallet specifically for DASH and &lt;a href=&quot;https://bankinnovation.net/2017/07/after-long-wait-apple-oks-dash-wallet-for-ios-app-store/&quot;&gt;was created by the DASH Foundation, so there is no reason to worry about scams and counterfeit apps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dash-wallet/id1206647026?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Link to the DASH wallet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Z-Cash was approved for the App Store too, but is only available via Jaxx&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zcash was the first anonymous cryptocurrency to get Apple’s blessings. There was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.z.cash/t/zcash-and-jaxx-announce-zec-approved-and-live-on-ios-appstore/15227&quot;&gt;press release campaign in April 2017&lt;/a&gt; announcing Apple approved ZEC for App Store, and Jaxx integrated it. Right now the Jaxx wallet for iOS from April 2017 supports both DASH and ZEC, &lt;strong&gt;even though the description of the app on iTunes doesn’t say so&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jaxx was planning to integrate ZCASH &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jaxx_io/status/785833459772162048&quot;&gt;unce upon a time even along with Monero&lt;/a&gt; - but that doesn’t look very likely anymore. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, the problem with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.altcointrading.net/jaxx-vulnerability&quot;&gt;Jaxx is the security vulnerability of Jaxx desktop&lt;/a&gt; version. Recently there was also a problem with the servers on which the backend is running, and people were &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jaxx_io/status/883849413294256128&quot;&gt;unable to access their ETC funds for the whole weekend&lt;/a&gt;. There was no warning in the app, it just showed old data apparetly from a backup, and the app was frozen - not a nice way to persuade people to store their monies in it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, although the iOS app is not suffering from the vulnerability of the desktop wallet, it is currently &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/jaxx-blockchain-wallet/id1084514516?mt=8&quot;&gt;collecting negative reviews on the App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monero people, don’t get ahead of yourselves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monero’s situation is even better! There is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/monero-wallet-by-freewallet/id1126426159?mt=8&quot;&gt;Monero wallet approved by the App Store&lt;/a&gt; right now but as slick as it looks, it is a scam. It has been a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Monero/comments/5lrnw8/anyone_use_the_monero_app_on_the_apple_app_store/&quot;&gt;known scam for at least six months&lt;/a&gt; yet it is still available on the wonderful Apple App Store with diligent app reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 10:38:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.altcointrading.net/ios-dash-wallet-app</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.altcointrading.net/ios-dash-wallet-app</guid>
        
        
        <category>altcoins</category>
        
        <category>dash</category>
        
        <category>wallets</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ETH multisig hack</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a reason for the selloff, if you are looking for one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DFHvB86W0AEOnX0.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some multisig wallets with contracts for ICOs created with certain versions of Parity are vulnerable and getting drained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far all ICO money for Edgeless Casino, aeternity and swarm.city is gone. It is 153k ETH which was worth about $32M when the heist started. At the moment it is around $30M. &lt;a href=&quot;https://etherscan.io/address/0xb3764761e297d6f121e79c32a65829cd1ddb4d32#internaltx&quot;&gt;This is where the coins were sent to&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bug has not been fixed yet so the draining might be going to continue for a while longer, unless money is moved out of vulnerable wallets in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The vulnerability is a serious one, allegedly one only needs the public key and certain kind of metadata and that is enough to regenerate the wallet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://press.swarm.city/parity-multisig-wallet-exploit-hits-swarm-city-funds-statement-by-the-swarm-city-core-team-d1f3929b4e4e&quot;&gt;Some of the funds were secured by ways of the same hack by a group of white hackers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Swarm: A swift response from a whitehat hacker group used the same exploit to drain many other project’s parity multisig wallets, in order to protect them from theft. This group was able to save over 377,000 ETH. Unfortunately the 44,055 ETH that was in Swarm City’s wallet is gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Black hat hacker wallet address with stolen ether: https://etherscan.io/address/0xb3764761e297d6f121e79c32a65829cd1ddb4d32&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;White hat wallet address with preserved ether: https://etherscan.io/address/0x1dba1131000664b884a1ba238464159892252d3a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bug has been fixed - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/paritytech/parity/commit/e06a1e8dd9cfd8bf5d87d24b11aee0e8f6ff9aeb&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 16:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.altcointrading.net/eth-multisig-hack</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.altcointrading.net/eth-multisig-hack</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where to trade blackbytes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two days ago, on the full moon, there was a blackbytes airdrop. If you signed a message with a BTC address before the deadline on 9th of July, you received free &lt;strong&gt;bytes&lt;/strong&gt; and some hours later also some &lt;strong&gt;blackbytes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the bytes can be traded on &lt;a href=&quot;https://bittrex.com/Market/Index?MarketName=BTC-GBYTE&quot;&gt;Bittrex (by millions as GBYTE)&lt;/a&gt;, the blackbytes aren’t traded anywhere. To trade these for bytes you need to sign up to the byteball slack channel &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.byteball.org/&quot;&gt;via the autoinviter here&lt;/a&gt; and head to #trading_blackbyte channel. The channel has a bot that works as an order book by Gigabyte per Gigablackbyte:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.prntscr.com/image/D2NJV0HoTAqCiTrhnt38OQ.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently the top of the ask book is at 0.01290 GB/GBB and top of the bid book at 0.02008 GB/GBB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gigabytes per bitcoin are trading at Bittrex around 0.24 BTC ($585).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about-byteball&quot;&gt;About Byteball&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Byteball is a payment network that makes it easy to set conditional payments - &lt;em&gt;finalize payment only if condition is met&lt;/em&gt; - similar to ethereum smart contracts but more user-friendly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wiki.byteball.org/uploads/slackjore/bind-400.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way transactions are confirmed is from the high level similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.altcointrading.net/iota&quot;&gt;IOTA’s tangle&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Transactions created by users are cryptographically linked to each other, and once you add your new transaction, other users start adding theirs on top of yours, and the number of other transactions that link to your transaction grows like snowball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In byteball this is called DAG (directed acyclic graph) - every new transaction references one or more earlier ones by including and signing their hashes. By including its parents, each new transaction also indirectly includes and confirms all parents of the parents, parents of the parents of the parents, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The supply is capped, there is no mining:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The total number of bytes is 10^15, all bytes were issued in the genesis transaction. Since the fees paid are returned into the circulation, the money supply will remain the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between bytes and blackbytes is that blackbytes have enhanced privacy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Private payments can be made using blackbytes, a cash-like untraceable currency. Its transactions are not visible on the public database that shows all payments made with (white)bytes. Blackbytes are sent peer-to-peer instead in an encrypted chat session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=1608859.0&quot;&gt;Read more at bitcointalk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;byteball-airdrops&quot;&gt;Byteball airdrops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you didn’t catch the first airdrop, there will be another one the next full moon (August 7th) - &lt;a href=&quot;https://byteball.org&quot;&gt;byteball.org&lt;/a&gt; has a countdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-to-get-into-the-next-airdrop&quot;&gt;How to get into the next airdrop&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enter the byteball giveaway you need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://byteball.org/#download&quot;&gt;download byteball wallet&lt;/a&gt; and from it &lt;a href=&quot;byteball:A2WMb6JEIrMhxVk+I0gIIW1vmM3ToKoLkNF8TqUV5UvX@byteball.org/bb#0000&quot;&gt;enter the chat window with the transition bot&lt;/a&gt;. The bot will tell you to first state your byteball address, then your bitcoin addresses each followed by a message signed with that address. The signed message must contain only your byteball address.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 02:35:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.altcointrading.net/byteball</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.altcointrading.net/byteball</guid>
        
        
        <category>altcoins</category>
        
        <category>trading</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Economics of Proof of Stake</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-gist-of-pos&quot;&gt;The gist of PoS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mailchimpfix&quot;&gt; &lt;amp-iframe width=&quot;400px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; layout=&quot;fixed&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-modals allow-popups allow-forms&quot; src=&quot;https://amp2disqus.netlify.com/altcointrading/signup.html&quot;&gt;&lt;amp-img layout=&quot;fill&quot; src=&quot;/img/ads/ad-placeholder.jpg&quot; placeholder=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;&lt;/amp-iframe&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In PoW (Proof of work) the longest chain is valid, as in the one with most &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt;. In PoS the one that is agreed upon in betting &lt;em&gt;consensus&lt;/em&gt; is accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the proposed version of proof of stake in ETH, stakers make bets on which block will be included in the blockchain. The block that is backed up by most bets is the winning one. The betting is automated and has several rounds as the odds of reaching consensus at each block changes. The initial bets are small, when a leader starts to emerge the bets grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The betting happens automatically. All the staker has to do is to put a full node online and lock up their stake for four months. In the last published at least 32 ETH is needed to participate in staking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;will-staking-pay-off&quot;&gt;Will staking pay off?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one wants to focus only on profits, staking could be compared to lending at an exchange. Bets made on the winning block get rewarded, the rest is lost. That means there will have to be losses too, but thanks to the system of several betting rounds the losses should be small - the bets start small and move higher once there’s higher confidence regarding the winning block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is simply lots of tiny gambles with the odds in the staker’s favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a counterparty risk as well though: staker loses his lot if it appears that he is engaged in an illicit anti-network activity. This ban from staking is for Vitalik and his crew to judge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another small risk comes from volatility of ETH - should a big dump be obvious, staker cannot withdraw his money to sell, but this can be hedged with the help of derivatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But practically, staking could be more profitable than lending on an exchange, just probably not for individuals at home as they’d have to run a full node. Running a full node costs energy, maintenance and bandwidth and we all know that even though setting up a parity wallet to make a basic transaction is a matter of an hour max, the full ethereum blockchain has a fat ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There probably is an incentive for the ETH fanbois to prefer staking to lending on an exchange though, because as stakers they would be “helping the good cause”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that Vitalik is aware of these sentiments that are outside of economics, but it is anyone’s guess if he has plans to use them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;/img/daddyvitalik/IsHeForReal.png&quot;&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;border&quot;&gt;&lt;amp-img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;/img/daddyvitalik/IsHeForReal.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; width=&quot;700px&quot; height=&quot;360px&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: From Vitalik’s medium.com post &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@VitalikButerin/a-proof-of-stake-design-philosophy-506585978d51&quot;&gt;“A Proof of Stake Design Philosophy”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-is-it-really-with-the-centralization-and-unfair-advantages&quot;&gt;How is it really with the centralization and unfair advantages&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most promoted advantage of proof of stake is that it fights centralization of mining that seems to always emerge in PoW after some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PoW&lt;/strong&gt;: If you are late to the party or don’t have access to cheap electricity or don’t have enough capital to constantly upgrade your mining equipment, your mining profits will not pay for your expenses - at least not until your coin increases in price, and if you should be waiting for that it would make more sense to simply trade. In addition to this you are fighting mining cartels that might be engaged in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.cornell.edu/~ie53/publications/btcProcFC.pdf&quot;&gt;selfish mining&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Selfish Mining”: A group of miners can form a pool that behaves as single agent […] following some strategy. Selfish-Mine allows a pool &lt;strong&gt;of sufficient size&lt;/strong&gt; to obtain a &lt;strong&gt;revenue larger than its ratio of mining power&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The key insight behind the selfish mining strategy is to force &lt;strong&gt;the honest miners into performing wasted computations on the stale public branch&lt;/strong&gt;. […] Selfish miners achieve this goal by selectively revealing their mined blocks to invalidate the honest miners’ work. Approximately speaking, the selfish mining pool &lt;strong&gt;keeps its mined blocks private&lt;/strong&gt;, secretly bifurcating the blockchain and creating a private branch. Meanwhile, the honest miners continue mining on the shorter, public branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PoS&lt;/strong&gt;:
If ETH main office says you cheat, you lose your stake. If ETH main office says you are honest, you get transaction fees and the block reward. Your profit is proportional to how much you stake, nothing else - there is no difficulty, there will be some hardware maintenance but not as much as with PoW. If you have more starting capital you will earn more, but proportionally more - you are not supposed to get an edge when you have more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put it bluntly, if everything should work as drafted it would mean that the business of &lt;em&gt;staking&lt;/em&gt; would not scale the way the business of &lt;em&gt;mining&lt;/em&gt; does, but  while at the same time &lt;em&gt;staking&lt;/em&gt; would not pay off for small individual participants, similarly as with &lt;em&gt;mining&lt;/em&gt; of well established coins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of anti-capitalistic compromise understandably causes some stir, but Vitalik is clearly bigger than that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;/img/daddyvitalik/yeswecan.png&quot;&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;border&quot;&gt;&lt;amp-img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;/img/daddyvitalik/yeswecan.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; width=&quot;700px&quot; height=&quot;360px&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BitfuryGeorge/status/883177297309839360&quot;&gt;@BitfuryGeorge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to add to this: it is not even quite clear that PoS is really free from all this unfairness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s  not clear&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Staker A owns 100 ETH and stakes all 100 of it. Staker B owns 100 000 ETH and stakes all of it but into 1000 different accounts. Has Staker B has 1000x chance to find the block over Staker A?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What if all the stakers are the same staker? How would anyone know?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answers to this would &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; be that this is an attack, there might be a fork - you know the drill. It is unclear how would this be detected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If a staker-attacker has an ETH short equal or more than his stake and is the majority network validator, then the staker-attacker has nothing to lose. The currency will lose in value but the staker-attacker has the short to profit from the drop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there is an argument that it is not possible to short this much ETH on any exchange, it might be possible in the future if there are more highly leveraged futures or option markets available. One could also long Alt/ETH pairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “nothing at stake” problem: In the case of a consensus failure stakers have nothing to lose by voting for multiple blockchain-histories, which prevents the consensus from ever resolving. Because there is little cost in working on several chains (unlike in proof-of-work systems), anyone can abuse this problem “for free”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one Ethereum implementation called &lt;em&gt;slasher&lt;/em&gt;, this behavior would fall under “cheating” and would lead to the loss of the stake, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/economic-modeling/tree/master/casper&quot;&gt;but slasher introduces other problems&lt;/a&gt; - what if most staking nodes drop out (blockchain generation freezes, called “ice age”) and what if there is no consensus (blockchain generation gets stuck). You can read the whole mildly technical explanation &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/economic-modeling/tree/master/casper&quot;&gt;at ethereum’s github&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/wiki/wiki/Proof-of-Stake-FAQ&quot;&gt;Casper should work with some form of slashing conditions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Ethereum roadmap, &lt;a href=&quot;https://np.reddit.com/r/ethereum/comments/609yjl/vladzamfir_if_the_price_of_ether_stays_high_i/df4r7hq/&quot;&gt;the switch to PoS is planned for June 2018&lt;/a&gt; (the switch has been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/When-will-ethereum-switch-to-proof-of-stake&quot;&gt;postponed several times&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;strong&gt;At this stage, of course PoS in ETH is not ready yet,&lt;/strong&gt; but what is the hype all about, really?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PoS is not convenient for big miners, it is not convenient for hobby miners/stakers, it is not convenient for traders &amp;amp; holders because it introduces new possible problems and reasons for forks - but it’s the next big thing because it is a system that is “more fair” and also “eco friendly”? Quite serious there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frankly it does not really scream advantages, other than what relates to “Vitalik philosophy”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;/img/daddyvitalik/VitalikTheLordSavior.png&quot;&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;border&quot;&gt;&lt;amp-img itemprop=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;/img/daddyvitalik/VitalikTheLordSavior.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; width=&quot;700px&quot; height=&quot;360px&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image: From Vitalik’s medium.com post &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@VitalikButerin/a-proof-of-stake-design-philosophy-506585978d51&quot;&gt;“A Proof of Stake Design Philosophy”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/wiki/wiki/Proof-of-Stake-FAQ&quot;&gt;https://github.com/ethereum/wiki/wiki/Proof-of-Stake-FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/economic-modeling/tree/master/casper&quot;&gt;https://github.com/ethereum/economic-modeling/tree/master/casper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs.cornell.edu/~ie53/publications/btcProcFC.pdf&quot;&gt;Paper on Selfish Mining&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-13-jul-17&quot;&gt;Update, 13 Jul ‘17&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TuurDemeester&quot;&gt;Tuur Demeester&lt;/a&gt; published &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@tuurdemeester/critique-of-buterins-a-proof-of-stake-design-philosophy-49fc9ebb36c6&quot;&gt;critique of Vitalik’s piece on the PoS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ethereum/comments/6mvu7m/critique_of_buterins_a_proof_of_stake_design/dk50ny4/&quot;&gt;Vitalik’s response and discussion here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.altcointrading.net/pos</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.altcointrading.net/pos</guid>
        
        <category>popular</category>
        
        
        <category>eth</category>
        
        <category>altcoins</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trezor might be getting Monero, too</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Could it be that Trezor people don’t want to lose their customers for Ledger?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In mid June 2017 the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.altcointrading.net/ledger-monero&quot;&gt;CTO of Ledger wallet said on Reddit they would implement Monero, someday&lt;/a&gt;. There is no ETA yet and probably will not be any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, Slush of Satoshi Labs (the company behind Trezor wallet) is probably not willing to be left behind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/2017/06/28/slush-monero.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/slushcz/status/783654392071323649&quot;&gt;Link to tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any time scale of this is as unclear as with the Ledger wallet though:&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Monero/comments/68ulcx/would_raising_money_for_the_development_of/dh2kril/&quot;&gt; Slush apparently doesn’t have time to work on this so he is looking for someone from the Monero community to do the code.&lt;/a&gt; There already is an older implementation of Monero into the Trezor firmware and it needs modifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steemit.com/programming/@arcitecx/bounty-5-btc-for-xmr-implementation-on-trezor&quot;&gt;According to a post from Steemit, Slush apparently offers 5 BTC for this gig.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:09:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.altcointrading.net/trezor-monero</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.altcointrading.net/trezor-monero</guid>
        
        
        <category>xmr</category>
        
        <category>altcoins</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
